[
  {
    "id": 3601,
    "question": "extrañar",
    "questionDetails": "Imposible extrañar a alguien que llevarás siempre en el corazón.",
    "answer": "miss, surprising, wondered",
    "answerDetails": "Impossible to miss someone who will always be in heart."
  },
  {
    "id": 3602,
    "question": "matarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Si viene cerca de mi familia, voy a matarlo.",
    "answer": "kill him",
    "answerDetails": "If he comes near my family, I’m going to kill him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3603,
    "question": "entregó",
    "questionDetails": "Basados en evidencia fabricada que ella les entregó.",
    "answer": "handed, delivered, handed over",
    "answerDetails": "Based on fabricated evidence that she handed to them."
  },
  {
    "id": 3604,
    "question": "regresó",
    "questionDetails": "Y un mes dejó la casa y no regresó.",
    "answer": "returned",
    "answerDetails": "And then one month he left home and never returned."
  },
  {
    "id": 3605,
    "question": "bárbaro",
    "questionDetails": "Gertrude es tan refinada que nos quedamos todos pasmados ante el bárbaro comportamiento de sus hijos.",
    "answer": "barbarian, barbaric",
    "answerDetails": "Gertrude is so refined that we were all stunned by her children’s barbarian behavior."
  },
  {
    "id": 3606,
    "question": "santos",
    "answer": "Santos, saints, holy ones"
  },
  {
    "id": 3607,
    "question": "manejo",
    "questionDetails": "Su manejo de la situación fue excepcional.",
    "answer": "management, handling, operation",
    "answerDetails": "His management of the situation was exceptional."
  },
  {
    "id": 3608,
    "question": "demonio",
    "questionDetails": "La monja fue poseída por un demonio y aterrorizó al pueblo durante semanas.",
    "answer": "demon, devil, fiend",
    "answerDetails": "The nun was possessed by a demon and terrorized the town for weeks."
  },
  {
    "id": 3609,
    "question": "leyes",
    "questionDetails": "Las leyes de privacidad son super estrictas ahora.",
    "answer": "laws, legislation",
    "answerDetails": "Because privacy laws are super strict nowadays."
  },
  {
    "id": 3610,
    "question": "conocerlo",
    "questionDetails": "Usted tiene que conocerlo.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "You must know her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3611,
    "question": "ponernos",
    "questionDetails": "Ponernos ciegos, e irnos por ahí en barca.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "Get loaded, and take the boat out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3612,
    "question": "ministerio",
    "questionDetails": "Él está entrenando para el Ministerio.",
    "answer": "ministry",
    "answerDetails": "He is training for the ministry."
  },
  {
    "id": 3613,
    "question": "ilusiones",
    "questionDetails": "El idealismo no es algo malo, pero hacerse demasiadas ilusiones no llevará a ningún cambio.",
    "answer": "wishful thinking",
    "answerDetails": "Idealism isn’t a bad thing, but too much wishful thinking won’t lead to any change."
  },
  {
    "id": 3614,
    "question": "conseguiste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Conseguiste trabajo finalmente? ¡ Felicitaciones!.",
    "answer": "did you get, you got",
    "answerDetails": "Did you get a job finally? Congratulations!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3615,
    "question": "sacarte",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes que sacarte tus zapatos.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "You gotta take those shoes off."
  },
  {
    "id": 3616,
    "question": "sana",
    "questionDetails": "Fue una relación completamente legal y sana.",
    "answer": "healthy, heals, sound",
    "answerDetails": "It was a totally legal and healthy relationship."
  },
  {
    "id": 3617,
    "question": "abrí",
    "questionDetails": "Abrí la puerta, y el gato entró.",
    "answer": "i opened",
    "answerDetails": "I opened the door, and the cat came in."
  },
  {
    "id": 3618,
    "question": "adivina",
    "questionDetails": "La adivina le dijo a la mujer que tendría 4 hijos varones.",
    "answer": "diviner",
    "answerDetails": "The diviner told the woman that she’d have four sons."
  },
  {
    "id": 3619,
    "question": "mientas",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que le mientas a tus padres mejor que eso.",
    "answer": "lie",
    "answerDetails": "I hope you lie to your parents better than that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3620,
    "question": "ayuden",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo amigos que me ayuden.",
    "answer": "help, assist",
    "answerDetails": "I have no friends to help me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3621,
    "question": "inversión",
    "questionDetails": "Esta pregunta requiere una inversión entre el sujeto y el verbo.",
    "answer": "inversion",
    "answerDetails": "This question requires the inversion of the subject and verb."
  },
  {
    "id": 3622,
    "question": "graves",
    "questionDetails": "La barra que desear cuando se trata de graves.",
    "answer": "bass",
    "answerDetails": "The bar lacking when it comes to bass."
  },
  {
    "id": 3623,
    "question": "dispara",
    "questionDetails": "Dispara a las alas.",
    "answer": "shoot, fires, triggers",
    "answerDetails": "Shoot the wings off the flies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3624,
    "question": "culpables",
    "questionDetails": "Nos sentimos tan culpables.",
    "answer": "guilty, culprits, blame",
    "answerDetails": "We feel so guilty."
  },
  {
    "id": 3625,
    "question": "decirnos",
    "questionDetails": "Ese anciano piensa que puede decirnos qué hacer.",
    "answer": "tell us",
    "answerDetails": "That old man thinks he can tell us what to do."
  },
  {
    "id": 3626,
    "question": "pierdes",
    "questionDetails": "Si no tú pierdes.",
    "answer": "lose",
    "answerDetails": "If not you lose."
  },
  {
    "id": 3627,
    "question": "avisó",
    "questionDetails": "Fue su espíritu quien te avisó.",
    "answer": "warned, alerted, tipped",
    "answerDetails": "It was her spirit that warned you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3628,
    "question": "límites",
    "questionDetails": "La estupidez de algunos parece no tener límites.",
    "answer": "bounds",
    "answerDetails": "The stupidity of some people appears to know no bounds."
  },
  {
    "id": 3629,
    "question": "medias",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Qué frío hace! ¡ Ojalá llevara medias gruesas!.",
    "answer": "tights, hosiery",
    "answerDetails": "It’s really cold today! I wish I was wearing thick tights!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3630,
    "question": "mochila",
    "questionDetails": "Roger se detuvo al lado del sendero para sacar un tentempié de su mochila.",
    "answer": "rucksack",
    "answerDetails": "Roger stopped on the side of the trail to get a small snack out of his rucksack."
  },
  {
    "id": 3631,
    "question": "lágrimas",
    "questionDetails": "No ha habido lágrimas.",
    "answer": "tears",
    "answerDetails": "There had been no tears."
  },
  {
    "id": 3632,
    "question": "cogido",
    "questionDetails": "Lo ha cogido al volver de la escuela.",
    "answer": "caught, picked up, grabbed",
    "answerDetails": "Caught it coming home from school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3633,
    "question": "preparo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo preparo sus comidas.",
    "answer": "prepare",
    "answerDetails": "I prepare her meals."
  },
  {
    "id": 3634,
    "question": "valores",
    "questionDetails": "Es una buena chica con muy sólidos valores.",
    "answer": "values, securities",
    "answerDetails": "She’s a good girl with a strong set of values."
  },
  {
    "id": 3635,
    "question": "ciego",
    "questionDetails": "Tratan de ciegos con la ciencia.",
    "answer": "blind, caecum",
    "answerDetails": "They try to blind you with science."
  },
  {
    "id": 3636,
    "question": "casé",
    "questionDetails": "Me casé con el primero que me miró.",
    "answer": "married, get married",
    "answerDetails": "I married the first man who looked at me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3637,
    "question": "colegas",
    "questionDetails": "Un par de mis colegas.",
    "answer": "colleagues, peers, buddies",
    "answerDetails": "A couple colleagues of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 3638,
    "question": "favorita",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hermana siempre fue la favorita de nuestros padres.",
    "answer": "favorite",
    "answerDetails": "My sister was always my parents’ favorite."
  },
  {
    "id": 3639,
    "question": "marcas",
    "questionDetails": "Sí, de las mismas marcas y lo antes posible.",
    "answer": "brands, marks, trademarks",
    "answerDetails": "The same brands, and as soon as possible."
  },
  {
    "id": 3640,
    "question": "plazo",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero un préstamo de corto plazo.",
    "answer": "term, period, deadline",
    "answerDetails": "I want a short-term loan."
  },
  {
    "id": 3641,
    "question": "pulso",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando te despiertes, pero antes de levantarte, mira tu pulso en Reposo.",
    "answer": "pulse",
    "answerDetails": "When you wake up, but before you get out of bed, check your resting pulse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3642,
    "question": "copas",
    "questionDetails": "Incluso las aguas en cuencos y copas.",
    "answer": "cups, glasses, drinks",
    "answerDetails": "Even waters in bowls and cups."
  },
  {
    "id": 3643,
    "question": "caí",
    "questionDetails": "Me caí y me golpeé.",
    "answer": "fell, dawned, crashed",
    "answerDetails": "I fell and hurt myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 3644,
    "question": "seco",
    "questionDetails": "La Costa Oeste ha tenido 2 inviernos secos en una fila.",
    "answer": "dry, dried",
    "answerDetails": "The West Coast has had two dry winters in a row."
  },
  {
    "id": 3645,
    "question": "caída",
    "questionDetails": "La caída de la red de la compañía retrasó el lanzamiento del nuevo software.",
    "answer": "crash, dropping, hang",
    "answerDetails": "The crash of the company’s network delayed the release of the new software."
  },
  {
    "id": 3646,
    "question": "entenderlo",
    "questionDetails": "Pero ha de entenderlo.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "But he’s got to understand."
  },
  {
    "id": 3647,
    "question": "obtener",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos dispuestos a obtener un récord.",
    "answer": "get, obtain",
    "answerDetails": "We’re keen to get a record out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3648,
    "question": "lógica",
    "questionDetails": "Antes de que digas que no, déjanos explicarte la lógica de la propuesta.",
    "answer": "rationale, logic",
    "answerDetails": "Before you say no, let us explain the rationale behind the proposal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3649,
    "question": "nace",
    "questionDetails": "El Orinoco es un enorme río venezolano. Nace en la sierra de Parima.",
    "answer": "it begins",
    "answerDetails": "The Orinoco is a huge Venezuelan river. It begins in the Parima Mountains."
  },
  {
    "id": 3650,
    "question": "cientos",
    "questionDetails": "Cientos de millones de dólares.",
    "answer": "hundreds, thousands",
    "answerDetails": "Hundreds of millions of dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 3651,
    "question": "cajón",
    "questionDetails": "La engrapadora está en el cajón superior izquierdo.",
    "answer": "drawer",
    "answerDetails": "The stapler is in the top left drawer."
  },
  {
    "id": 3652,
    "question": "pequeñas",
    "questionDetails": "Disfruto la satisfacción de hacer bien las cosas pequeñas.",
    "answer": "small, little, tiny",
    "answerDetails": "I enjoy the satisfaction of doing small things well."
  },
  {
    "id": 3653,
    "question": "tendrían",
    "questionDetails": "Si hubieran ido al supermercado, como sugerí, tendrían todos los ingredientes del pastel.",
    "answer": "they would have",
    "answerDetails": "If they’d gone to the grocery store, as I suggested, they would have all the ingredients for the cake."
  },
  {
    "id": 3654,
    "question": "nacimiento",
    "questionDetails": "También descendió la tasa de nacimiento.",
    "answer": "birth",
    "answerDetails": "Also the birth rates lowered."
  },
  {
    "id": 3655,
    "question": "político",
    "questionDetails": "Como político, me supera hasta a mí.",
    "answer": "politician",
    "answerDetails": "As a politician he exceeds even myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 3656,
    "question": "celosa",
    "questionDetails": "Solo estabas celosa cuando él estaba fuera.",
    "answer": "jealous",
    "answerDetails": "You were only jealous when he was away."
  },
  {
    "id": 3657,
    "question": "gonzález",
    "answer": "Gonzalez"
  },
  {
    "id": 3658,
    "question": "ratas",
    "questionDetails": "Pero no es para tus ratas.",
    "answer": "rats, mice",
    "answerDetails": "But it is not for your rats."
  },
  {
    "id": 3659,
    "question": "lleguen",
    "questionDetails": "Pero cambiará cuando lleguen mis hijos.",
    "answer": "arrive, reach",
    "answerDetails": "But that will all change when my sons arrive."
  },
  {
    "id": 3660,
    "question": "bendito",
    "questionDetails": "Ha sido un bendito alivio.",
    "answer": "blessed",
    "answerDetails": "It was a blessed release."
  },
  {
    "id": 3661,
    "question": "presa",
    "questionDetails": "Abrieron la puerta de la presa para soltar el agua.",
    "answer": "dam, prey, reservoir",
    "answerDetails": "They opened the dam’s gate to let the water flow."
  },
  {
    "id": 3662,
    "question": "colmo",
    "questionDetails": "El colmo en los árboles verdes profundos creció orquídeas coloridas.",
    "answer": "high",
    "answerDetails": "High in the deep green trees grew colorful orchids."
  },
  {
    "id": 3663,
    "question": "huyendo",
    "questionDetails": "La gente está huyendo de la ciudad.",
    "answer": "fleeing, running, escaping",
    "answerDetails": "People are fleeing the city."
  },
  {
    "id": 3664,
    "question": "condena",
    "questionDetails": "Tiene condenas previas, pero lleva 15 años fuera de la prisión y sin consumir sustancias ni alcohol.",
    "answer": "conviction, sentence, condemnation",
    "answerDetails": "He has prior convictions, but he’s been out of prison and clean and sober for 15 years."
  },
  {
    "id": 3665,
    "question": "representante",
    "questionDetails": "No es muy buen representante.",
    "answer": "agent",
    "answerDetails": "Not a very good agent."
  },
  {
    "id": 3666,
    "question": "prometió",
    "answer": "Promised"
  },
  {
    "id": 3667,
    "question": "creerlo",
    "questionDetails": "Oímos que la tienda había cerrado pero no podíamos creerlo.",
    "answer": "believe it",
    "answerDetails": "We heard the store had closed down but couldn’t believe it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3668,
    "question": "porfa",
    "answer": "Porfa"
  },
  {
    "id": 3669,
    "question": "sois",
    "questionDetails": "Para mí, vosotros dos sois.",
    "answer": "are, thou art",
    "answerDetails": "For me you two are."
  },
  {
    "id": 3670,
    "question": "fábrica",
    "questionDetails": "La empresa tiene programado abrir nuevas fábricas en China.",
    "answer": "plant, mill, factory",
    "answerDetails": "The company plans to open new plants in China."
  },
  {
    "id": 3671,
    "question": "huir",
    "questionDetails": "Se vio obligado a huir del país.",
    "answer": "flee, escape",
    "answerDetails": "He was forced to flee the country."
  },
  {
    "id": 3672,
    "question": "rastro",
    "questionDetails": "No se puede caminar por la nieve sin dejar algún rastro.",
    "answer": "trace, trail",
    "answerDetails": "You cannot walk on snow without leaving some trace."
  },
  {
    "id": 3673,
    "question": "amenazó",
    "questionDetails": "Él amenazó a mi vida en realidad.",
    "answer": "threatened",
    "answerDetails": "He threatened my life actually."
  },
  {
    "id": 3674,
    "question": "celebrando",
    "questionDetails": "Pensó que debía estar celebrando algo.",
    "answer": "celebrating, welcoming",
    "answerDetails": "She thought she must be celebrating something."
  },
  {
    "id": 3675,
    "question": "universo",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito más que rocio y jugo de universo.",
    "answer": "universe",
    "answerDetails": "I need lot more than dew and the universe juice."
  },
  {
    "id": 3676,
    "question": "sagrado",
    "questionDetails": "A un oficial de policía nada es sagrado.",
    "answer": "sacred, holy, hallowed",
    "answerDetails": "To a police officer nothing is sacred."
  },
  {
    "id": 3677,
    "question": "amenazas",
    "questionDetails": "Durante el desayuno siempre recibo amenazas graves.",
    "answer": "threats, menaces, threatened",
    "answerDetails": "I get serious threats every morning."
  },
  {
    "id": 3678,
    "question": "importar",
    "questionDetails": "Decidir cómo desea importar el sonido.",
    "answer": "import",
    "answerDetails": "Decide how you want to import sound."
  },
  {
    "id": 3679,
    "question": "acostumbrada",
    "questionDetails": "Ya veo que está acostumbrada a la buena vida.",
    "answer": "accustomed, used, wonted",
    "answerDetails": "I can tell you’re accustomed to fine living."
  },
  {
    "id": 3680,
    "question": "acerques",
    "questionDetails": "No te acerques al bar.",
    "answer": "near",
    "answerDetails": "Do not go near the bar."
  },
  {
    "id": 3681,
    "question": "bosque",
    "questionDetails": "¿Quieres dar un paseo por el bosque?",
    "answer": "woods, woodland",
    "answerDetails": "Do you want to take a walk through the woods?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3682,
    "question": "testimonio",
    "questionDetails": "Si das testimonio falso, te puedan acusar de haber cometido perjurio.",
    "answer": "witness, testament",
    "answerDetails": "If you bear false witness, you can be accused of having committed perjury."
  },
  {
    "id": 3683,
    "question": "sacan",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces le sacan la venda.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "Then they take the blindfold off."
  },
  {
    "id": 3684,
    "question": "pasillo",
    "questionDetails": "El pasillo era largo y estaba mal iluminado.",
    "answer": "hallway, corridor, aisle",
    "answerDetails": "The hallway was long and poorly lit."
  },
  {
    "id": 3685,
    "question": "cumpla",
    "questionDetails": "Cumpla mis demandas en el plazo de una hora o …",
    "answer": "comply, meet, conforms",
    "answerDetails": "Comply with my demands within the hour, or …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3686,
    "question": "cercano",
    "questionDetails": "Ella dijo que hay un patio de recreo cercano.",
    "answer": "nearby",
    "answerDetails": "She said there’s a playground nearby."
  },
  {
    "id": 3687,
    "question": "verlas",
    "questionDetails": "Nos alegramos tanto de verlas.",
    "answer": "see",
    "answerDetails": "We are so happy to see you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3688,
    "question": "traemos",
    "questionDetails": "Traemos más al grupo.",
    "answer": "bring",
    "answerDetails": "Bring more into the fold."
  },
  {
    "id": 3689,
    "question": "arrancar",
    "questionDetails": "Una revolución es necesaria para arrancar el orden social.",
    "answer": "uproot",
    "answerDetails": "A revolution is necessary to uproot the social order."
  },
  {
    "id": 3690,
    "question": "encontrarme",
    "answer": "Meet"
  },
  {
    "id": 3691,
    "question": "soñé",
    "questionDetails": "Tan sólo nunca soñé.",
    "answer": "dreamed",
    "answerDetails": "I just never dreamed."
  },
  {
    "id": 3692,
    "question": "suficientemente",
    "questionDetails": "María dice que sale con hombres mayores, ya que los hombres de su edad no son suficientemente maduros.",
    "answer": "sufficiently, adequately",
    "answerDetails": "Maria says she dates older men, because men her age are not sufficiently mature."
  },
  {
    "id": 3693,
    "question": "aprovecha",
    "questionDetails": "Rainfinity aprovecha los estándares de la industria sin la introducción …",
    "answer": "leverages, take advantage, exploits",
    "answerDetails": "Rainfinity leverages industry standards without introducing …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3694,
    "question": "arrepentido",
    "questionDetails": "El acusado fue arrepentido por lo que había hecho.",
    "answer": "remorseful",
    "answerDetails": "The defendant was remorseful for what he had done."
  },
  {
    "id": 3695,
    "question": "hombro",
    "questionDetails": "Me disloqué el hombro al caerme del caballo.",
    "answer": "shoulder",
    "answerDetails": "I dislocated my shoulder when I fell from my horse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3696,
    "question": "pantalla",
    "questionDetails": "Su pelo giró a través de la pantalla de su cara.",
    "answer": "screen, display",
    "answerDetails": "Her hair swung across to screen her face."
  },
  {
    "id": 3697,
    "question": "profesión",
    "questionDetails": "De profesión.",
    "answer": "profession",
    "answerDetails": "By profession."
  },
  {
    "id": 3698,
    "question": "montado",
    "questionDetails": "Y que se hubiesen montado en el mismo tren que la …",
    "answer": "mounted",
    "answerDetails": "And that had mounted in the same train that the …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3699,
    "question": "platos",
    "questionDetails": "¿Ya lavaste los platos?",
    "answer": "dishes",
    "answerDetails": "Did you wash the dishes already?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3700,
    "question": "enseñado",
    "answer": "trained"
  }
]